Gio Meneses

Chicago, Illinois

📕 (+01)786-624-7130 | 💌 giomeneses42@gmail.com | 🖸 giomeneses | 🛅 giomeneses | He/Him

Summary

IT Manager with 15+ years of professional IT experience managing systems, and software while supporting people with humility and integrity. I am curiosity-driven and enthusiastic about all things tech & I have experience performing various roles such as - Systems Administrator, IT-Help Desk Support, AV Administrator and Sound Engineer. During my career I have had the opportunity to learn and work with various tools, services, and methodologies. Among others - Jamf, Okta, AWS, GCP, DockerHub, GitHub, CircleCI, Ansible, Jira(agile sprints) and Confluence.

Work Experience

Outfox Hospitality (Foxtrot Market merged with Dom's Kitchen & Market)

Chicago, IL

IT Systems Manager February 2024 - April 2024

- Led IT integration projects between both companies which utilized internal resources resulting in an estimated cost savings of \$40,000
- · Spearheaded the migration project which transitioned all users and emails from Microsoft 365 to Google Workspace
- Managed a team of 3 which ensured the smooth operation of 600+ user devices, 100+ point-of-sale devices, and the accompanying network infrastructure
- · Responsible for End User Computing, Store Infrastructure, and Cybersecurity across both Foxtrot and Dom's Kitchen & Market combined 34 stores
- · On-boarded approximately 300 employees onto a unified IT system which and enhanced collaboration within the newly combined company
- · Coordinated the necessary steps and processes as the company closed its operations, minimizing disruptions and ensuring compliance

Foxtrot Market Chicago, IL

IT Systems Manager February 2023 - February 2024

- · Achieved monthly cost reduction of \$6,000 by strategically implementing cost-cutting measures and renegotiating contracts
- Oversaw the design, procurement, and seamless integration of IT hardware infrastructure, enabling the opening of 9 new stores in 2023
- · Architected and managed HappyFox ticketing system which streamlined communication and issue resolution across 8 teams and 5 departments
- Managed IT hardware and infrastructure across 33 stores in 3 regions Chicago, DMV, and Texas
- Using KnowBe4 I designed and conducted targeted simulations to enhance employee awareness and Cybersecurity vigilance
- Revamped on/off-boarding procedures which streamlined orientation processes and automated administrative tasks, resulting in improved efficiency and employee experience
- Facilitated the transition of all technology assets within a commissary to a new owner-operator, ensuring continuity and minimal disruption of the operation

Civis Analytics Chicago, IL

SENIOR IT SUPPORT SPECIALIST & IT SUPPORT SPECIALIST

October 2018 - November 2022

- Developed and maintain an automated CircleCI pipeline to sync Jamf policies and the associated code with GitHub to create a single source of truth
- Sped up a key Ansible playbook by 85% that saved the IT and DevOps teams 15 minutes per run when creating VPN accounts
- Using various AWS services(such as ACM, EC2, ELB, Security Groups, Route53), I deployed a self-hosted Snipe-IT instance to keep track of assets throughout their life-cycle
- · Crafted a zero touch provisioning process using DEPNotify allowing new hires to unbox their new machine with little to no input from IT
- Develop and maintain scripts, pkgs, and policies for a macOS environment using various tools/languages like Vim, Jamf, Git, Bash, and Python
- Following FedRAMP & SOC 2 controls I administer and maintain two secure Okta environments along with the accompanying 130+ SSO apps
- Manage/Support SaaS apps like Adobe CC, G Suite/GCP, Slack, Jamf, Box, GitHub, DockerHub, CircleCl, Office 365, and SentinelOne
- Lead new hires through our biweekly IT on-boarding sessions to finalize account and laptop setup
- Manage Google Meet conference rooms and expanded the AV capabilities of the Chicago and DC offices
- Implement and manage Jira ServiceDesk projects for multiple teams which includes support queues for internal and external customers
- · Participate in a round robin support queue for internal support tickets, while serving as an escalation point for junior team members
- · Manage inventory of laptops, iPads, software licenses, and other consumables while working with procurement to order/renew on a regular cadence

UptakeChicago, IL

AV Support Administrator & IT Support Administrator

- · Managed and ran monthly company all hands events as well as monthly leadership team meetings
- Managed 60+ Zoom conference rooms alongside all the Zoom user accounts
- Researched and designed a mobile AV rig that I used for internal and external events
- · Researched, and acquired hardware to record the CEO's podcast
- Trained all new hires on all the AV solutions that were used in the company
- · Attended Infocomm the premiere Pro-AV convention in 2017, and 2018 and brought back knowledge to implement new hardware and solutions
- Provided IT and AV support to the company during a time of rapid growth from about 400 employees to 800
- Provisioned laptops and on-boarded about 20 new hires every two weeks
- Provided executive support to VIP users which included the CEO and other C level executives

Northwestern University

Chicago, IL

TECHNICAL SUPPORT SPECIALIST & USER SUPPORT REPRESENTATIVE

October 2013 - August 2016

August 2016 - October 2018

- Provided remote and onsite IT support to around 5000 faculty and staff in a secure HIPAA environment across multiple buildings on campus
- Created new documentation with Confluence to lower the amount of ticket escalations
- · Was responsible for providing IT and AV support to Executive MBA students, faculty, and staff on class weekend
- Completed weekly, monthly, and annual maintenance on all campus equipment which included classrooms, study group rooms, and common
 areas
- Acted as interim senior IT consultant during a period of transition
- · Worked with Senior IT leadership to replace the aging Ricoh printers and replaced them with a new Canon fleet of printers
- Administered the VOIP telecommunications system for the campus

Education

Apple Certified Support Professional

Chicago, IL

10.11 MAVERICKS

Miami, Florida

A.A COMPUTER INFORMATION SYSTEMS

2015

2020 - Present

2016

Skills/Tools

Miami-Dade College

SaaS/Management Tools JAMF(Pro, Connect, Protect), Kandji, G Suite, SentinelOne, Code42, Okta, Slack, GitHub, Jira, Confluence

Operating Systems macOS, Ubuntu/Linux, Windows & WSL2

Development Bash/Zsh, Git, Markdown, Python, Regex, Vim, YAML **DevOps** AWS, GCP, Docker, Ansible, CircleCl, TravisCl, Pulumi

Languages English, Spanish, Google

Hobbies 3D Printing, Mini Painting, Sim Racing, Photography, Board games

For Fun_

PROXMOXVE/RASPBERRYPI

Homelab Servers Chicago, IL

• Using Ansible and Docker-Compose I manage my ProxmoxVE server that runs my home automation and simple website

- Pi-Hole server that that blocks Ads and internet tracking while also functioning as my local DNS and DHCP server
- · RaspberryPi running OctoPi server that manages 3D printer allowing for remote management of print jobs

 Hobbyist Photographer
 Earth

 FUJIFILM X-T5 & X100F
 2014 - Present

- XF 16-80m F4, XF 35 F2, Vivitar 55m F2.8 AutoMacro
- · Self hosted portfolio at photos.meneses.dev

APRIL 26, 2024 GIO MENESES · RÉSUMÉ